[Music]
black cumin also known as nigela sativa
or simply black seed is not actually
related to cumin it's a member of the
Buttercup rather than carrot family
black cumin is used in Indian and Middle
Eastern Cuisines just like any other
regular spice and has a peppery flavor
but it's also been prized for purported
medicinal benefits described as a
miracle herb with mentions going back to
the Old Testament it was found cashed in
King tutt's tomb for instance and
Prophet Muhammad is evidently quoted as
saying black human could heal every
disease except death only in the last 50
years or so has it been put to the test
though culminating more than a thousand
papers published in the medical
literature typical doses used in studies
are just one or two gram a day which is
only about a/4 teaspoon this enables
researchers to perform randomized double
bond Placebo control trials by stuffing
the whole food spice powdered into
capsules rather than studying some
component or extract systematic reviews
and meta analyses of randomized control
trials have found that daily black human
consumption significantly improves
cholesterol
triglycerides blood
pressure and blood sugar
control some of the results were quite
extraordinary for example one study
found that post-menopausal women
randomized to a gram a day which is less
than a/4 teaspoon of black cumin powder
reduced their LDL cholesterol by
27% within two months significantly
better than Placebo those are the kind
of results you'd expect from a Statin
drug yet this was just a sprinkles worth
of a simple spice black cumin may even
help with menopausal symptoms now it
didn't cure anything a month after
stopping the spice cholesterol levels
started to creep back up but it does
appear to be a cheap safe effective and
delicious if you like things spicy
treatment for some of our deadliest risk
factors and the side effects loss of
appetite and weight loss
Bingo the latest systematic review and
meta analyses of randomized controlled
weight loss trials found that about a/4
teaspoon of black cumin powder every day
does appear to cause weight loss within
a span of a few months if it really can
benefit so many facets of heal
why don't you hear more about it why
wasn't I taught about it in medical
school maybe because there's little
profit motive black C is just a common
natural spice the daily dose used in
most of these studies would cost about 3
cents a day you're not going to Thrill
your stockholders by selling something
you can't patent that costs 3 cents a
day black cumin has become a staple in
my family's daily diet you can just keep
a a pepper mill filled with it uh right
on the kitchen table grinded on Foods
just like black pepper easy and
delicious
[Music]